A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, Rockefeller Boards, Series O FA324
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Bureau of Social Hygiene
  - Bureau of Social Hygiene - General, 1927-1960 (Box 8, Folder 61)
    Plans for Institute of Criminological Research; lease of space by Bureau of Social Hygiene; Dunham's resignation; Harrison's resignation as Director. Assignment of Bureau of Social Hygiene royalties to Sealantic Fund. Preparation of Manual for Policewomen; liquidation of Bureau of Social Hygiene. Correspondents include Raymond B. Fosdick, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur Woods, Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Arthur W. Packard, L. U. Harrison, L. B. Dunham.
  - Bureau of Social Hygiene - George J. Kneeland, 1914-1924 (Box 8, Folder 62)
    Investigator for Bureau of Social Hygiene; employment by War Camp Community Service. John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contribution for treatment, support, funeral expenses. Correspondents include George Kneeland, Raymond B. Fosdick, Charles O. Heydt, Willard S. Richardson, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Bureau of Social Hygiene - New York City Department of Health - Venereal Disease Clinic, 1911-1914 (Box 8, Folder 63)
    Bureau of Social Hygiene contribution to clinic. Correspondents include Hermann Briggs, Jerome D. Greene, Starr J. Murphy.
  - Bureau of Social Hygiene - Johns Hopkins Hospital, 1914-1920 (Box 8, Folder 64)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s contribution through Bureau of Social Hygiene for establishment of special department at hospital for study and treatment of syphilis. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., George Walker, William Welch, Simon Flexner, Dr. W. H. Smith.
  - Bureau of Social Hygiene - Gustavus Myers, 1910 (Box 8, Folder 65)
    Copy of Myers' article from which he prepared his pamphlet, "The White Slave Traffic in New York City." Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Gustavus Myers.
  - Bureau of Social Hygiene - New York Evening Journal, 1910-1913 (Box 8, Folder 66)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. requested facts about Wheeler murder, in which murderer alleged to be "cadet" in white slave traffic. Publication of Reverend Cock's book on "Engagement and Marriage." Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Arthur Brisbane, W. R. Hearst.
  - Bureau of Social Hygiene - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - January 1913 Statement (Box 9, Folder 67)
    Press release on "The Origin, Work and Plans of the Bureau of Social Hygiene." Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Bureau of Social Hygiene - Police Investigation, 1912-1913 (Box 9, Folder 68)
    Coordination with work of citizens' committee to arrest those implicated in Rosenthal murder; summary of proposed work; minutes; plans for publication of report. Correspondents include Jerome D. Greene, Robert Binkerd, Starr J. Murphy.
  - Bureau of Social Hygiene - Police Investigation - Aldermanic Committee, 1912-1913 (Box 9, Folder 69)
    Appointment of E. R. Buckner as General Counsel; copy of report.
  - Bureau of Social Hygiene - Police Investigation - Bureau of Municipal Research, 1912-1913 (Box 9, Folder 70)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pays Bureau's investigation expenses.
  - Bureau of Social Hygiene - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Pledges, 1911-1925 (Box 9, Folder 71)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributions to Dr. Davis' salary, special research problems, costs of Committee for Research on Sex Problems and State Police investigation. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Willard S. Richardson, Charles O. Heydt.
  - Bureau of Social Hygiene - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Pledges, 1926-1949 (Box 9, Folder 72)
  - Bureau of Social Hygiene - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. - Traffic in Women and Children, 1923-1929 (Box 9, Folder 73)
    Financing of Bureau of Social Hygiene study, under auspices of League of Nations, of traffic in women and girls.
  - Bureau of Social Hygiene - Police Lieutenants' Benevolent Association, 1911-1912 (Box 9, Folder 74)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. accepts invitation to Association dinner; copy of his speech, "The Police Force from a Citizen's Point of View." Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Lt. Richard Enright, Jacob Riis.
  - Bureau of Social Hygiene - Publications, 1906-1916 (Box 9, Folder 75)
    Pamphlets on "White Slave" report; publications of American Social Hygiene Association; reports on syphilis and prostitution; grand jury presentment; report on investigation. Distribution of "House of Bondage."
  - Bureau of Social Hygiene - Publications, 1906-1916 (Box 9, Folder 76)
  - Bureau of Social Hygiene - Publications, 1906-1916 (Box 9, Folder 77)
  - Bureau of Social Hygiene - Annual Reports to Trustees, 1928-1930 (Box 10, Folder 78)
  - Bureau of Social Hygiene - Annual Reports to Trustees, 1931 (Box 10, Folder 79)
  - Bureau of Social Hygiene - Reorganization, 1913, 1927-1932 (Box 10, Folder 80)
    Notice of meeting; election of members of executive committee. Resignation of Dr. Davis and Charles O. Heydt; election of Arthur Woods and John D. Rockefeller 3rd. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. pledges to special projects; certificate of change of purposes and operations of Bureau of Social Hygiene. Correspondents include Charles O. Heydt, Dr. Katharine Bement Davis, Thomas M. Debevoise, Arthur Woods, John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Bureau of Social Hygiene - Julia Richman - Correspondence, 1911-1913 (Box 10, Folder 81)
    Reports of Mothers' Club work; needs of school girls in Miss Richman's district; termination of employment. Employment of Miss Geffen; Mrs. Garrett's lectures on sex hygiene. Death of Miss Richman. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Julia Richman, Starr J. Murphy, Katherine Geffen.
  - Not Used (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - Bureau of Social Hygiene - Hattie Ross - Correspondence, 1910-1911 (Box 10, Folder 83)
    Furnishing of data on "white slave traffic." Correspondents include Hattie Ross, Charles O. Heydt.
  - Bureau of Social Hygiene - Howard B. Woolston, 1916-1928 (Box 10, Folder 84)
    Preparation of study of prostitution in America; salary arrangements; grant of expenses. Revision of book; termination of employment. Correspondents include Abraham Flexner, Howard B. Woolston, Raymond B. Fosdick, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Katharine Bement Davis, James Reynolds.
  - Bureau of Social Hygiene - "House of Bondage" Distribution, 1910 (Box 10, Folder 85)
  - Bureau of Social Hygiene - "House of Bondage" Distribution, January-February 1911 (Box 10, Folder 86)
  - Bureau of Social Hygiene - "House of Bondage" Distribution, March-October 1911 (Box 10, Folder 87)
- China Medical Board
  - China Medical Board - China Commission, 1914 (Box 11, Folder 88)
    Commission to investigate medical conditions in China.
    File Plan note
    3
  - China Medical Board - Report of China Commission, 1915 (Box 11, Folder 89)
    Summary report and sectional reports by Frederick T. Gates, Dr. Simon Flexner and Dr. Welch.
  - China Medical Board - Annual Reports, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 90)
    Dr. Buttrick's preliminary report dealing with progress up to 1917.
  - China Medical Board - China Conference of the Rockefeller Foundation, 1914 (Box 11, Folder 91)
    Minutes of the "China Conference of the Rockefeller Foundation, New York City, January 19-20, 1914. President John D. Rockefeller, Jr. occupied the chair.
  - China Medical Board - Incorporation, By-Laws, 1915 (Box 11, Folder 92)
    Obtaining approval of Secretary of State. Certificate of incorporation (including draft rejected by Secretary of State); minutes of organizational meetings.
  - China Medical Board - Memoranda, 1914-1918 (Box 11, Folder 93)
    Estimates of China Medical Board needs, 1917; thoughts on medical missions and the spirit and teaching of Jesus; scholarships for Chinese nurses; 1915 plan for development of hospitals in China; Greene memo on land tenure by foreigners in China; Commission of Study recommendations. January 15, 1915 conference - agreements to form Peking Union Medical College; 1916 memos about missionary work. Correspondents include Roger S. Greene, Wallace Buttrick, Frederick T. Gates.
    3A
  - China Medical Board - General, 1914-1930 (Box 11, Folder 94)
    Founding of Board; purchase of Union Medical College at Peking; study trip to China and Japan; relations with missionary societies and Chinese government; appropriations; Peking Union Medical College policy; Finance Committee correspondence; administrative matters; war relief, Japanese threat; advisability of sending more funds into China. Board elections, resignations, appointments; final gift from Rockefeller Foundation to China Medical Board. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Roger S. Greene, Richard M. Pearce, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Wallace Buttrick, Starr J. Murphy, Charles O. Heydt, Ivy Lee, Thomas M. Debevoise, George E. Vincent.
  - China Medical Board - General, 1931-1938 (Box 11, Folder 95)
    Founding of Board; purchase of Union Medical College at Peking; study trip to China and Japan; relations with missionary societies and Chinese government; appropriations; Peking Union Medical College policy; Finance Committee correspondence; administrative matters; war relief, Japanese threat; advisability of sending more funds into China. Board elections, resignations, appointments; final gift from Rockefeller Foundation to China Medical Board. Correspondents include Roger S. Greene, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Winthrop W. Aldrich, Thomas M. Debevoise, George E. Vincent, Dr. Henry S. Houghton, Edwin C. Lobenstine, Raymond B. Fosdick, Alan Gregg, John A. Brown.
  - China Medical Board - General, 1939-1944 (Box 11, Folder 96)
    Founding of Board; purchase of Union Medical College at Peking; study trip to China and Japan; relations with missionary societies and Chinese government; appropriations; Peking Union Medical College policy; Finance Committee correspondence; administrative matters; war relief, Japanese threat; advisability of sending more funds into China. Dr. Forkner's post-war trip to China; Board's failure to renew Forkner's salary. Board elections, resignations, appointments; final gift from Rockefeller Foundation to China Medical Board. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Thomas M. Debevoise, Edwin C. Lobenstine, Claude E. Forkner.
  - China Medical Board - General, 1945-1947 (Box 11, Folder 97)
    Founding of Board; purchase of Union Medical College at Peking; study trip to China and Japan; relations with missionary societies and Chinese government; appropriations; Peking Union Medical College policy; Finance Committee correspondence; administrative matters; war relief, Japanese threat; advisability of sending more funds into China. Dr. Forkner's post-war trip to China; Board's failure to renew Forkner's salary. Board elections, resignations, appointments; final gift from Rockefeller Foundation to China Medical Board. Correspondents include Roger S. Greene, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Thomas M. Debevoise, Bertram Cutler, Edwin C. Lobenstine, Claude E. Forkner, Arthur W. Packard, Barton Turnbull, Philo W. Parker.
  - China Medical Board - General, 1948-1961 (Box 11, Folder 98)
    Founding of Board; purchase of Union Medical College at Peking; study trip to China and Japan; relations with missionary societies and Chinese government; appropriations; Peking Union Medical College policy; Finance Committee correspondence; administrative matters; war relief, Japanese threat; advisability of sending more funds into China. Dr. Forkner's post-war trip to China; Board's failure to renew Forkner's salary. Board elections, resignations, appointments; final gift from Rockefeller Foundation to China Medical Board. Dr. Loucks's reports from his Far East visit, 1955. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Harold H. Loucks, Philo W. Parker, Chester Barnard, Edgar B. Young, Joseph C. Hinsey.
  - Not Used (Box 11, Folder 99)
  - China Medical Board - Report of the China Medical Commission to the Rockefeller Foundation, 1914 (Box 011A, Folder 0089A)
    Starr J. Murphy's copy.
  - China Medical Board - Report of the China Medical Commission to the Rockefeller Foundation, 1914 (Box 011A, Folder 0089A)
  - China Medical Board - Aid to Mission Hospitals, 1916-1917 (Box 12, Folder 100)
    Discussion of Roger S. Greene's recommendation regarding aid to mission hospitals.
  - China Medical Board - Henry Sturgis Grew Memorial Fund, 1916-1923 (Box 12, Folder 101)
    Fund established by Jane Norton Grew to operate Harvard Medical School of China, Inc.; China Medical Board's absorption of fund to set up Shanghai Medical School; return of fund to Harvard. Correspondents include Wallace Buttrick, Starr J. Murphy, Edwin Embree, Louis G. Myers, Bertram Cutler, Roger S. Greene, A. L. Boulware.
    3.2
  - China Medical Board - Roger S. Greene - Resignation, 1934-1935 (Box 12, Folder 102)
    Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, M. Eggleston, Raymond B. Fosdick, Alan Gregg, George E. Vincent, Jerome D. Greene, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, F. H. Hawkins, A. E. Cohn.
  - China Medical Board - Grants and Endowment from Rockefeller Foundation, 1935-1947 (Box 12, Folder 103)
    History of relations of Foundation, China Medical Board and Peking Union Medical College; 1936 financial rearrangement; 1947 termination grant.
  - China Medical Board - Dr. Edwin C. Lobenstine - Retirement Dinner, 1945 (Box 12, Folder 104)
    Dinner in honor of Dr. Lobenstine's retirement from China Medical Board, May 31, 1945; copy of John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s remarks.
  - China Medical Board - Review of Policy, 1954, 1953-1955 (Box 12, Folder 105)
    Relation of China Medical Board to Rockefeller Foundation; relation of John D. Rockefeller 3rd to Peking Union Medical College; future of Peking Union Medical College - nationalized by Reds; decision to continue spending in Orient.
  - China Medical Board - Incorporation and By-Laws, 1928-1939 (Box 12, Folder 106)
    By-laws and certification of incorporation of China Medical Board, Inc.; China Medical Board of Rockefeller Foundation deeded to China Medical Board, Inc. Certificates of amendments to charter, by-laws; minutes. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, C. B. Belknap, George E. Vincent.
    3B
  - China Medical Board - Study of Chinese Investments, 1933-1934 (Box 12, Folder 107)
    Activities and report of John D. Rockefeller 3rd as a special committee of one to study the advisability and feasibility of the Board's investing funds in China. Correspondents include Lefferts M. Dashiell, Barton Turnbull, Bertram Cutler, Roger S. Greene, Raymond B. Fosdick, John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    3C
  - China Medical Board - Peking Union Medical College - Historical Sketch and Description of Buildings, 1922 (Box 12, Folder 108)
  - China Medical Board - Peking Union Medical College - Correspondence, 1916-1932 (Box 12, Folder 109)
    Progress reports; hiring of D.W. Deshlev from Standard Oil of New York; request for portraits of John D. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, Jr.; letters of gratitude from those treated at Peking Union Medical College. Board's acquisition of college; commemorative medal struck by China; requests for aid; budgets; policy on appointments; investigation by Minister of Education. Dr. Henry S. Houghton's reports on disintegrating political and military situation; closing of College by Japanese; internment of Americans; question of creating new Peking Union Medical College in free China; descriptions of Japanese treatment of College. End of war and restoration of College; replacement estimates and claims against Japanese; use of Peking Union Medical College by General Marshall's Commission to China. Progress of refitting; re-opening. Includes unsigned correspondence of June 4, 1925 from Dr. Stephen C. Duggan to Thomas W. Lamont assessing China's attitudes toward foreigners. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, Abraham Flexner, F. H. Hawkins, Wallace Buttrick, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., George E. Vincent, Roger S. Greene, R. H. Kirk, Thomas M. Debevoise, Dr. Stephen C. Duggan, Charles O. Heydt, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, M. Eggleston.
    3.1 and 3.2
  - China Medical Board - Peking Union Medical College - Correspondence, 1933-1935 (Box 12, Folder 110)
    Progress reports; hiring of D.W. Deshlev from Standard Oil of New York; request for portraits of John D. Rockefeller and John D. Rockefeller, Jr.; letters of gratitude from those treated at Peking Union Medical College. Board's acquisition of college; commemorative medal struck by China; requests for aid; budgets; policy on appointments; investigation by Minister of Education. Dr. Henry S. Houghton's reports on disintegrating political and military situation; closing of College by Japanese; internment of Americans; question of creating new Peking Union Medical College in free China; descriptions of Japanese treatment of College. End of war and restoration of College; replacement estimates and claims against Japanese; use of Peking Union Medical College by General Marshall's Commission to China. Progress of refitting; re-opening. Correspondents include Starr J. Murphy, Abraham Flexner, F. H. Hawkins, Wallace Buttrick, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., George E. Vincent, Roger S. Greene, R. H. Kirk, Thomas M. Debevoise, Charles O. Heydt, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, M. Eggleston.
  - China Medical Board - Peking Union Medical College - Correspondence, 1936-1945 (Box 13, Folder 111)
  - China Medical Board - Peking Union Medical College - Correspondence, 1946-1958 (Box 13, Folder 112)
  - China Medical Board - Peking Union Medical College - Report on Re-Opening, 1946 (Box 13, Folder 113)
  - China Medical Board - Peking Union Medical College - Memoranda, 1920-1921 (Box 13, Folder 114)
    Salaries; actions of Board in regards to construction of College.
    3.1
  - China Medical Board - Peking Union Medical College - Buildings, 1916-1918 (Box 13, Folder 115)
    Relations with Mr. Coolidge and Shattuck and Hussey, architects.
  - China Medical Board - Peking Union Medical College - Y. T. Tsur, 1934-1936 (Box 13, Folder 116)
    Chairman of Board of Peking Union Medical College. Resignation of Roger S. Greene as director; appointment of Dr. Henry S. Houghton as representative; divorce of China Medical Board and Peking Union Medical College Boards - problem of inter-board confusion.
  - China Medical Board - Peking Union Medical College - Dinner, May 12, 1938 (Box 13, Folder 117)
    Dinner for Dr. Henry S. Houghton.
  - China Medical Board - Peking Union Medical College - Letter to Dr. Henry S. Houghton, 1938-1941 (Box 13, Folder 118)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. letter dated October 2, 1940, designed to smooth out deteriorating inter-board relations. Related correspondence.
  - China Medical Board - Peking Union Medical College - Claims, 1921-1924 (Box 13, Folder 119)
    Claim of Permutit Company settlement by Lucy Fletcher Brown against Peking Union Medical College.
  - China Medical Board - Peking Union Medical College - Release of Dr. Henry S. Houghton, 1942-1945 (Box 13, Folder 120)
    Efforts to obtain release of internees. Dr. Henry S. Houghton and Mr. Bowen finally liberated, 1945.
  - China Medical Board - Peking Union Medical College - Letter to Foreign Mission Boards, 1915 (Box 13, Folder 121)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s letter to missionary boards explaining China Medical Board; arrangements with missionary boards controlling Union Medical College; agreement with London Missionaries Societies. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Wallace Buttrick, Starr J. Murphy, Missionary Societies.
  - China Medical Board - Peking Union Medical College - Incorporation, Lease, Charter, 1915-1917 (Box 13, Folder 122)
    Correspondence about charter; application for incorporation.
  - China Medical Board - Peking Union Medical College - Land Title, Permanent Organization, 1915-1926 (Box 13, Folder 123)
    Tenure of land by foreigners in China. Correspondents include Roger S. Greene, Starr J. Murphy, Wallace Buttrick, A. L. Boulware, W. C. Dennis, Thomas M. Debevoise, F. H. Hawkins.
  - China Medical Board - Peking Union Medical College - Reports, 1916 (Box 14, Folder 124)
    "Preliminary Report" by Charles A. Coolidge, November 1916.
  - Proposed Buildings for the China Medical Board in East City, Peking (map), 1916 (Drawer B 1, Folder 91A)
  - China Medical Board - Peking Union Medical College - Reports, circa 1916-1917 (Box 14, Folder 125)
    "Present Conditions at the Union Medical College in Peking, with Suggested Plans for Development" by Franklin C. McLean and Roger S. Greene.
  - China Medical Board - Peking Union Medical College - Reports, 1917 (Box 14, Folder 126)
    "Report to the China Medical Board and the Board of Trustees of the Union Medical College" by Franklin C. McLean, October 23, 1917.
  - China Medical Board - Peking Union Medical College - Reports, 1919 (Box 14, Folder 127)
    "Living Conditions in Peking" by Roger S. Greene, March 11, 1919.
  - China Medical Board - Peking Union Medical College - Reports, 1921 (Box 14, Folder 128)
    "Conference on Matters Concerning the Peking Union Medical College and China Medical Board," held at Gedney Farms Hotel, White Plains, New York, May 16-17, 1921.
  - China Medical Board - Peking Union Medical College - Reports, 1921-1922 (Box 14, Folder 129)
    "The China Medical Board in China," July 1921"Scientific Work in Schools and Colleges of the Nanking Shanghai Region" by S. D. Wilson, Assistant Professor of Chemistry at Peking Union Medical College, December 12, 1921."Report on the Pre-Medical School Situation Made to the Trustees of the Peking Union Medical College" by Paul Monroe, Chairman of the Board of Trustees, Peking Union Medical College, February 25, 1922.
  - China Medical Board - Peking Union Medical College - Social and Religious Work, 1929-1947 (Box 14, Folder 130)
    Relation of College to missionary activities; status of Department of Social and Religious Work. Correspondents include Thomas M. Debevoise, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Raymond B. Fosdick, Edwin C. Lobenstine, F. H. Hawkins, M. Eggleston.
  - China Medical Board - Shanghai Medical School, 1916-1924 (Box 14, Folder 131)
    Contract with St. John's University of Pennsylvania, Harvard University School of Medicine, Nanking Medical School. Agreement with architect; abandonment of plan; disposal of property. Correspondents include Wallace Buttrick, Frederick T. Gates, Starr J. Murphy, Thomas M. Debevoise, A. L. Boulware.
  - China Medical Board - Oriental Trip - Itinerary, 1921 (Box 14, Folder 132)
    Itinerary, travel plans and arrangements, expenses, members of party.
  - China Medical Board - Oriental Trip - General Correspondence, 1921-1924 (Box 14, Folder 133)
    Aid of dignitaries; tributes for John D. Rockefeller, Jr., thanks from him. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt.
  - China Medical Board - Oriental Trip - John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s Correspondence with John D. Rockefeller, 1921 (Box 15, Folder 134)
    Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., H. Naito, Soroku Ebara.
  - China Medical Board - Oriental Trip - Speeches, 1921 (Box 15, Folder 135)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr.'s address at the dedication of Peking Union Medical College, September 19, 1921; C. C. Nieh's address given in honor of John D. Rockefeller, Jr., September 27, 1921.
  - China Medical Board - Oriental Trip - Medical Conference, 1921; 2 copies (Box 15, Folder 136)
    "Programme of the Medical Conference, Peking Union Medical College, September 15-22, 1921."
  - China Medical Board - Oriental Trip - Japan, 1921-1924 (Box 15, Folder 137)
    Tribute to John D. Rockefeller, Jr.; correspondence with Mr. K. Murai.
  - China Medical Board - Oriental Trip - Letters to Chinese, 1921-1923 (Box 15, Folder 138)